barco.com 2016-06-02

# Privacy policy | Barco

Barco appreciates your interest in the company and wants to thank you for browsing our website. With this privacy statement we would like to inform you about the information Barco collects from web visitors and how this information is used.

Barco collects personally identifiable information from web visitors and customers with the purpose of providing a better, more personal experience and delivering better targeted services and information. Barco respects and protects the privacy of the individuals who visit the Barco website and personally identifiable information is not willfully disclosed to any third party without your permission as explained in this privacy policy. Your personally identifiable data are processed by Barco nv, with registered office at President Kennedypark 35, 8500 Kortrijk, Belgium. 

This privacy policy covers www.barco.com and all sites residing under this top domain.

  * How do we use your information?
  * What information do we collect and for which purposes?
  * Cookies
  * With whom does Barco share information?
  * How long will Barco keep my personal information?
  * Links to other sites
  * Newsletters & emails
  * Legal disclosures
  * Your passwords
  * Data security
  * Your rights
  * Consent
  * Changes to the privacy policy
  * Questions

## How do we use your information?

We will use your personal information for a number of purposes including:

  * To contact you (for example, if you ask for a quote we might contact you via phone or email to follow up)
  * To provide you with services (e.g. to send you a newsletter or a news alert, if you have asked for them)
  * To personalize the way barco.com content is presented to you (e.g. based on your profile as a registered user we might offer you dedicated content for your area of expertise.)
  * To analyze and optimize the operation, structure and presentation of barco.com content (e.g. based on page views and page viewing times, we can update the barco.com content to improve your experience)

We won't contact you for marketing purposes, or promote new services to you unless you specifically agree. You can opt-out of receiving direct marketing from us at any stage. If you have a my.barco account, you can sign into your account in order to update your personal information.

## What information do we collect and for which purposes?

  1. Barco gathers general information about the use of our websites, such as frequently visited pages, services and tools. This information is used to optimize contents and improve the overall site usability and experience. We only use aggregated data for this purpose, which do not allow identifying individual visitors to our site.

When you link up to the Barco website we automatically collect the following data:

    * Type of domain name used to gain access to the Internet (e.g. .com, .org)
    * The IP address used during the connection
    * Date and time of access to the site
    * Duration of site/page visit
    * Browser used
    * Operating system of your computer, tablet or handheld device
    * Search engine and metatags used to track the Barco website on the web
    * Type and nature of files or information downloaded.
  2. In addition to this we may ask web visitors for personally identifiable information when contacting us or signing up to a Barco service:

    * Information you provide to personalize your web experience e.g. your interests, preferences, opt-ins and future needs
    * Information you provide with the aim of obtaining feedback from Barco;
    * Information you provide as part of an application will be stored and processed for that purpose only;
    * Information you provide for contract negotiations;

We will primarily use this personally identifiable information to market or provide Barco products and services to you, as requested or agreed. Next to this, we may also use personally identifiable information to deliver information to you and to contact you regarding administrative notices, resolve disputes or troubleshoot problems.

## Cookies

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier, which is sent to your computer, tablet or mobile phone browser and is stored on your device's hard drive. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you have visited, but the only other personally identifiable information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself.

On Barco’s websites, cookies record information about your online preferences and allow us to improve the quality of our service and tailor the website to your interests or preferences. Users have the opportunity to set their browsers to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. The last of these means that certain personalized features cannot then be provided to that user and accordingly they may not be able to take full advantage of all of the website's features. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

Information supplied by cookies can help us to analyze the profile of our visitors and help us to provide you with a better user experience. For example, if on a previous visit you opted to view our website in French or accessed information about our healthcare products, this information is stored in a cookie so that next time you visit the barco.com website we serve you information in French or on healthcare again.

Please note that during your visits to Barco websites you may notice some cookies that are not related to Barco. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Flickr, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. Barco does not control the dissemination or use of these cookies. You should check the third party websites for more information about these.

Barco will not actively sell or make personally identifiable information available to parties other than Barco’s affiliates. We limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide services to you or in order to do their jobs.

## How long will Barco keep my personal information?

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you have with Barco. If you cancel your registration or delete your Barco account, the account is flagged so that we no longer use the personal information. However, the information stays on the system for a maximum of 5 years after your last interaction with any member of the Barco group of companies.

## Newsletters & emails

Barco may send you email communications and/or newsletters, based on your subscriptions or your business relation with Barco.   
We will only use your name and email address in order to inform you and/or to send you our newsletters.   
If you no longer wish to receive such communications, you can follow the unsubscribe instructions contained in each of the communications you receive. 

## Links to other sites 

The Barco website may contain links to other websites of product and service vendors, manufacturers and partner companies. The sites linked to by Barco are developed by people over whom Barco exercises no control. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data or solicit personal information and the privacy policy of the visited website will be applicable from the moment you enter the new domain.

## Legal disclosures

Barco may disclose personally identifiable information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to prevent injury or property damage. We will usually attempt to notify you when we are making such a disclosure, but we may not do so in an emergency or when we are prohibited by law or court order from giving such notice.

## Your passwords

Passwords may be required to access certain features of this website. You should never disclose your password to any third parties. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personally identifiable information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password.

## Data security

Barco is committed to taking reasonable steps to protect the personal information that you provide to us. We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards in place to protect your personal information against unauthorized access, improper use or disclosure and unauthorized modification. However the internet is an open system and as such Barco cannot guarantee that the personal information you submit will not be intercepted by others. All our employees and agents who have access to or are involved in the processing of personal information respect the confidentiality of personal information.

## Your rights 

In accordance with the Belgian Privacy Act of December 8, 1992, you are entitled to request Barco to provide you with additional information. You are also entitled to have access to the personal data processed relating to you and to have these data rectified in the event they would appear to be incomplete or inaccurate. Finally, you are entitled to object at any time and free of charge to the further processing of personal data in relation to you by sending us a request by regular mail or email with a copy of your ID card or other suitable identity document to the address mentioned below.

## Consent

By using the Barco website, you consent to the collection and use of your information as outlined in this policy. Barco may decide to change this privacy policy from time to time.

## Changes to the privacy policy

If we decide to change our privacy commitment, we will post those changes here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. 

## Questions

If you have questions or suggestions, please can contact us at: [privacy@barco.com](mailto:privacy@barco.com)

You have the right to access and, if necessary, correct your personal data. If you wish to do so, please send a dated and signed request with a copy of your ID card or other suitable identity document to Barco Corporate Marketing Department, President Kennedypark 35, 8500 Kortrijk, Belgium.

This document was last updated May 2012
